Codex CLI

If no subcommand is specified, options will be forwarded to the
interactive CLI.

Usage: codex [OPTIONS] [PROMPT]
       codex [OPTIONS] <COMMAND> [ARGS]

Commands:
  exec        Run Codex non-interactively [aliases: e]
  review      Run a code review non-interactively
  login       Manage login
  logout      Remove stored authentication credentials
  mcp         Manage external MCP servers for Codex
  mcp-server  Start Codex as an MCP server (stdio)
  app-server  [experimental] Run the app server or related
              tooling
  completion  Generate shell completion scripts
  sandbox     Run commands within a Codex-provided sandbox
  debug       Debugging tools
  apply       Apply the latest diff produced by Codex agent as a
              `git apply` to your local working tree [aliases: a]
  resume      Resume a previous interactive session (picker by
              default; use --last to continue the most recent)
  fork        Fork a previous interactive session (picker by
              default; use --last to fork the most recent)
  cloud       [EXPERIMENTAL] Browse tasks from Codex Cloud and
              apply changes locally
  features    Inspect feature flags
  help        Print this message or the help of the given
              subcommand(s)

Arguments:
  [PROMPT]
          Optional user prompt to start the session

Options:
  -c, --config <key=value>
          Override a configuration value that would otherwise be
          loaded from `~/.codex/config.toml`. Use a dotted path
          (`foo.bar.baz`) to override nested values. The `value`
          portion is parsed as TOML. If it fails to parse as
          TOML, the raw string is used as a literal.
          
          Examples: - `-c model="o3"` - `-c
          'sandbox_permissions=["disk-full-read-access"]'` - `-c
          shell_environment_policy.inherit=all`

      --enable <FEATURE>
          Enable a feature (repeatable). Equivalent to `-c
          features.<name>=true`

      --disable <FEATURE>
          Disable a feature (repeatable). Equivalent to `-c
          features.<name>=false`

      --remote <ADDR>
          Connect the app-server-backed TUI to a remote app
          server websocket endpoint.
          
          Accepted forms: `ws://host:port` or `wss://host:port`.

  -i, --image <FILE>...
          Optional image(s) to attach to the initial prompt

  -m, --model <MODEL>
          Model the agent should use

      --oss
          Convenience flag to select the local open source model
          provider. Equivalent to -c model_provider=oss; verifies
          a local LM Studio or Ollama server is running

      --local-provider <OSS_PROVIDER>
          Specify which local provider to use (lmstudio or
          ollama). If not specified with --oss, will use config
          default or show selection

  -p, --profile <CONFIG_PROFILE>
          Configuration profile from config.toml to specify
          default options

  -s, --sandbox <SANDBOX_MODE>
          Select the sandbox policy to use when executing
          model-generated shell commands
          
          [possible values: read-only, workspace-write,
          danger-full-access]

  -a, --ask-for-approval <APPROVAL_POLICY>
          Configure when the model requires human approval before
          executing a command

          Possible values:
          - untrusted:  Only run "trusted" commands (e.g. ls,
            cat, sed) without asking for user approval. Will
            escalate to the user if the model proposes a command
            that is not in the "trusted" set
          - on-failure: DEPRECATED: Run all commands without
            asking for user approval. Only asks for approval if a
            command fails to execute, in which case it will
            escalate to the user to ask for un-sandboxed
            execution. Prefer `on-request` for interactive runs
            or `never` for non-interactive runs
          - on-request: The model decides when to ask the user
            for approval
          - never:      Never ask for user approval Execution
            failures are immediately returned to the model

      --full-auto
          Convenience alias for low-friction sandboxed automatic
          execution (-a on-request, --sandbox workspace-write)

      --dangerously-bypass-approvals-and-sandbox
          Skip all confirmation prompts and execute commands
          without sandboxing. EXTREMELY DANGEROUS. Intended
          solely for running in environments that are externally
          sandboxed

  -C, --cd <DIR>
          Tell the agent to use the specified directory as its
          working root

      --search
          Enable live web search. When enabled, the native
          Responses `web_search` tool is available to the model
          (no perÔÇæcall approval)

      --add-dir <DIR>
          Additional directories that should be writable
          alongside the primary workspace

      --no-alt-screen
          Disable alternate screen mode
          
          Runs the TUI in inline mode, preserving terminal
          scrollback history. This is useful in terminal
          multiplexers like Zellij that follow the xterm spec
          strictly and disable scrollback in alternate screen
          buffers.

  -h, --help
          Print help (see a summary with '-h')

  -V, --version
          Print version
